The New Face of Horror
Midnight Movie is a horror, thriller, fantasy film directed by Jack Messitt.
At a seedy theater in a sleepy suburban town, a group of friends get together for a midnight screening of
an early 1970s horror film, unaware that the director has something more in store for them.
Bridget, played by Rebekah Brandes.
Josh, played by Daniel Bonjour.
Mario, played by Greg Cirulnick.
Samantha, played by Mandell Maughan.
Harley, played by Stan Ellsworth.
Babe, played by Melissa Steach.
A midnight movie is a low-budget genre picture or distinctly
nonmainstream film programmed for late-night screening or broadcast.
The term is rooted in the practice that emerged in the 1950s of local television stations around the United
States airing cheap genre films late at night, often with a host delivering ironic asides.
As a cinematic phenomenon, the midnight presentation of offbeat movies started toward the end
of the following decade in a few urban centers, particularly New York City.
The midnight run of El Topo at New York's Elgin Theater that began in December
1970 sparked a trend that eventually spread across the country.
The screening of nonmainstream pictures at midnight was aimed at building a cult film audience,
encouraging repeat viewing and social interaction in what was originally a countercultural setting.
The national after-hours success of The Rocky Horror Picture Show in the late 1970s and the changing economics of the film exhibition industry altered the nature of the midnight movie phenomenon; as its association with
broader currents of cultural and political opposition dwindled in the 1980s, the midnight movie became a more purely camp experience—in effect, bringing it closer to the television form that shares its name.
The term midnight movie is now often used in two different, though related, ways: as a synonym for B movie, reflecting the
relative cheapness characteristic of late-night movies both theatrically and on TV, and as a synonym for cult film.
The film explores themes of murder, urban legend, serial
killer, slasher, aftercreditsstinger.
The tone is dark and intense.